#### Contact

+353892047680 (Mobile) talhatkhan95@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/talhatkhan (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

.NET Framework
API Development
Software Development

#### Languages

English (Professional Working)
Hindko (Native or Bilingual)
Urdu (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

What is Data Science?
Open Source Tools for Data Science
Machine Learning with Python
Data Science Orientation
Python for Data Science and Al

#### **Publications**

A Benchmark Dataset for Sentiment Analysis of Users' Reviews on COVID-19 Contact Tracing Applications

Global User-Level Perception of COVID-19 Contact Tracing Applications: A Data-Driven Approach Using Natural Language Processing

**Explainable Event Recognition** 

An Explainable Regression Framework for Predicting Remaining Useful Life of Machines

# **Talhat Khan**

Ph.D. Researcher at the University of Limerick | Generative AI | Explainable AI

County Limerick, Ireland

# Summary

I am a Ph.D. Researcher in the Science Foundation Ireland (SFI) within the Computer Science and Information Systems Department at the University of Limerick. With a Master's in Computer Systems Engineering from the University of Engineering and Technology Peshawar, my focus lies in demystifying black box neural network models. My current area of research is creating Personalized Language models, fine-tuning LLMs, model merging, and mitigating hallucinations in LLMs. I also worked in Programmer and Software Developer roles. My job description involved developing software for the organization and deriving valuable insights from data to enhance policies.

## Experience

University of Limerick
Doctoral Researcher
November 2023 - Present (10 months)
County Limerick, Ireland

Federal Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education Programmer

April 2022 - September 2023 (1 year 6 months)

Islāmābād, Pakistan

Welltime Ltd Senior Software Developer July 2018 - April 2023 (4 years 10 months)

Glasgow, Scotland, United Kingdom

### Education

University of Limerick

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Artificial Intelligence · (October 2023)

University of Engineering & Technology Peshawar Master's degree, Computer Systems Engineering · (2020 - 2022)

University of Engineering & Technology Peshawar Bachelor's degree, Computer Systems · (2014 - 2018)